Abhijeet Pawar

Berlin, Germany \cdot 304abhijeet@gmail.com \cdot +49 176 754 07724

LinkedIn · Github

PROFILE

Engineering leader with an Entrepreneurial mindset and a 10 year track record of building product & product teams. I have experience building and scaling products for early and late-stage startups primarily in edtech, and fintech domains. I enjoy working at the intersection of product & tech and specialize in building & scaling distributed systems.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Java, Kotlin, Python Micro: Typescript, Javascript, React Postg

Microservices, CI/CD Postgres, DynamoDB

Kubernetes, Kafka Cloud, AWS, Azure, GCP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Neovarsity UG Feb 2023 - Present Co Founder & CTO

- Responsible for hiring, building and maintaining the product & the platform.
- Bootstrapped, built & scaled the product to 1k+ users.

Finmid GmbH Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

Founding Engineer

- Built the cards platform, credit scoring engine & open banking integrations that provided the foundational building blocks for the two products launched by Finmid.
- Led the team that developed of the core lending product for business customers driving initial discovery, developing API spec, API documentation, building transaction workflows, reconciliation, reporting
- Joined the team as the founding engineer & scaled it to 8+ engineers.

Moss GmbH Oct 2020 - Aug 2021

Senior Engineer

- Conceptualized & built the invoicing product including storage, approvals, and integrations with 3rd party systems like DATEV.
- Led the auto receipt matching feature that matches incoming receipts from emails to customer transactions for faster accounting & reconciliation.

N26 GmbH Apr 2018 - Aug 2020

Tech Lead

- Led the cards transaction team of 4 & co-led the cards group at N26 (3 teams with 10+ engineers)
- · Designed, rearchitected & built various core transaction sub-systems for high availability and throughput.
 - Redesigned the card authorizer to support high availability and zero downtime deployment, this
 component is one of the most critical components processing up to 20M transaction records/month
 - Redeveloped the card transaction system that supported high throughput transaction clearing
- Responsible for hiring & mentoring junior/mid-level engineers on the team, coordinating with PMs/EMs on the talent requirements for the team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Computer Science

LANGUAGES

English

Native Proficiency